I knew it. Oysters.
Dinosaurs are so easy!
Awww!
[fast forward]
Oh, stop.
There it is.
Aww...
Awww.
How many times do I have to do this?
Oh...
I'm sorry.
[ED]
Hello. - Hello.
Hello. Where am I?
Where are you? I'm at Shichigahama.
BBQ with flying tamome.
Only the members can tell the inside story.
Yes, that's why I'm here in Shichigahama!
I recommend it!
Let me tell you why I came to Shichigahama.
Well, I've been having a bit of trouble lately...
What is it?
Something like... ah, bye-bye, Struck...
You know, Aqua Clara gave us that water server, right?
Yes, thank you very much.
I've been drinking a lot of it.
Yes, I drink a lot.
I always drink from a paper cup.
There is a paper cup next to it.
But sometimes they don't have them.
There are times when they don't get refilled.
Like, "Oh, no! Like, "I can't drink.
How do you drink it?
There are times when I have to ask myself, "How can I drink it?
So I said, "Why don't you make your own cup?
That's a good idea.
That's what they said.
It's a waste of resources.
It's the SDGs, isn't it?
The world today is SDGs.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
That's why we decided to make our own cups.
Today, we're visiting Tico Glass Design Studio.
Thank you very much.
I'm going to make my own cup here.
It's really cool.
I saw a lot of pictures on Instagram.
I saw a lot of pictures on Instagram, and they were so beautiful and cute.
I'm not sure if I can make it.
I'm sure I'm clumsy.
I'm so clumsy that I'm afraid I'll mess it up.
I'm going to try my best to make a cute little cup.
Okay, let's go!
Let's go!
Looks like a cafe!
Seriously, the location is too good.
Knock 10 times.
Three.
Seino.
Six.
I can't say it.
Hello! I'm looking forward to working with you!
I'm sorry to disturb you!
I'm sorry to bother you, but I've just come in.
I would like to ask you what I should do from here.
I'm looking forward to hearing from you.
First of all, I would like to ask you to choose a glass.
I see.
You can choose any one you like?
You can choose any one you like.
That's a lot.
You can choose the one you like best.
It's already done.
I said, "I picked this one and made this one.
It's a very mature one.
The quality is amazing, isn't it?
I wonder if I can make this.
I'm starting to get worried.
But... you know... when you look at it...
The roughness here...
It's from my grandma's house.
So it's like we're digging into this cup of our choice?
Yes, that's right.
I see.
I don't know.
But I...
I drink water, right?
Yes, water.
But you can drink alcohol, too.
A lot.
So it's kind of easy to dig.
I'm thinking of something a beginner can do.
Oh, I see.
I see.
This one comes in a stylish shape, too.
This is cute.
Potatoes are cute, too.
There are many colors to choose from.
I see.
The colors are cute, too.
stylish
Renaissance
makes me want to do it!
Renaissance all by myself.
I don't know what to do.
It's intuition, right?
I'll do this one.
Black on black.
Then you can choose up to three design stickers.
I see.
Okay.
That's it.
Yes, sir.
There are so many!
What should we do with them?
So cute!
Hawaii.
That's nice.
You can bring it all the way to Hawaii!
Yay!
Cat prints.
There are so many different kinds!
Wait a minute. I'm serious.
There's one that looks like Tinkerbell.
There's one that looks like Tinkerbell, and there's one that looks like a glass shoe.
They're so cute!
There are so many Louie cats!
If I were Karen, I would have made three cats.
Let's do three.
What should I do? Mewska! That's a good one.
It's nice.
Linesai.
What's with the Linesai?
She said she didn't like them.
She said she was scared of them.
I don't know. This Tatzu-like thing is cool, too.
It's awesome.
It's kind of kawaii.
Oh my god, more and more of the members' preferences are being revealed.
I like dinosaurs.
I like it!
I want to go to Hawaii now, so I want a Hawaiian pattern.
I'll get this one!
I've decided!
Let's see, the title is...
People who want to go to Hawaii
I'm going to call it "A cup for people who want to go to Hawaii
A cup for people who want to go to Hawaii.A cup for people who want to go to Hawaii
I would like to make a
I've decided
My cup is
Dinosaur cup
I love it!
Hawaii and dinosaurs.
That's weird.
I don't know...
veteran
So, my tool set arrived!
For the first time since elementary school!
So, we just picked out 3 stickers for you.
This time, we were allowed to take some pictures of them.
We couldn't do it normally, but you made a special sticker with our names on it.
Thank you very much for making them!
They made stickers named Yuna and Waka!
They are so cute!
Thank you so much!
I've had name stickers made by someone other than my mom.
I'm so happy!
This time it's a little bit special.
I'd like to dig this one, too.
I'll get right on it.
I'll take care of it.
Please do.
Okay.
Now, let's put the first sticker out on the mat.
Yes, sir.
On the mat.
Then we'll use a knife.
We're going to use the knife to spray sand to engrave, so we're going to pull out the area where we're going to spray the sand.
I'm going to do a little bit of that.
I'm going to use the knife and I'm going to stick it in the squeak and I'm going to bring it up.
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
I see.
Once you get this far, then you can use your hand or a pen set.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, it's so easy.
You'll just have to watch.
Oh, oh, oh.
I see.
Oh, thank goodness... I thought I was supposed to dig through all of this.
Oh, good, great.
I'm so happy.
This... this... this... this...
I see.
I might have picked this one out if it wasn't so fine.
That's how it is, isn't it?
Wow.
I'm fine.
Oh, Kiyo!
Santa's cooking!
It's definitely easy for a dinosaur!
It sure is.
Because, you know...
Wait a minute!
Isn't this turtle the worst?
I know... but this hibiscus is the worst.
It's a nice holiday.
Holiday.
It's a holiday, right?
It's a holiday.
Now that's a risk?
Yes!
Oh no!
We have to leave the middle here in the middle.
That's what I mean.
That's right.
Oh my God, I can't believe I'm showing the world how serious I am.
This is so addictive.
It's so fun!
Oh, yeah, it's so much fun peeling dinosaurs off!
It's so much fun. It's so much fun to peel the dinosaurs.
I know, right?
It's so much fun!
Oh, it's finally here
Oh, it's so beautiful!
Wow, it's amazing!
But, it's like this circle, isn't it?
Yes.
Wow, there are 7 circles.
Yes, there are more.
Are you done already? Maybe...
Almost...
But I can already see
I can see a cute future.
So cute!
I'm so excited!
Finally, it's over!
Thank you!
Hibiscus Yuna
I still have a lot left to do!
I think the rest will be fine.
I know, it's easy around here.
But it's the balance of this that's the hard part.
Be careful with the balance!
What should I do?
Where to put it?
The face.
You're right.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
What was I supposed to do?
It's too far back in my memory. I only made it early.
I'm used to it by now, as you can imagine.
Dinosaurs are easy, when you think about it.
Dinosaurs were easy.
It's true.
I just chose that one, you know.
Maybe that dragon is easier than I thought.
Like you asked me earlier, what's the hardest?
Wagaran
Like Mandalan.
Oh, maybe that's what you were saying behind the scenes...
Oh, no, I didn't.
What should I do?
I said I could do it, but I couldn't do it at all.
Crispy, crispy, crispy.
I really thought I'd failed.
I thought I'd have to start all over again.
I'm going to do this, all of you.
I went the same way as everyone else.
This is gonna be hard.
Oh...
Don't cut out the middle of the "A".
No way.
I have no idea.
We started out together, but before I knew it...
I'm a teacher now.
You're right.
This isn't a good place.
I think it's good.
A little lower.
Oh, here.
Here.
Say "stop." Here.
Oh, stop, stop, stop.
How many times do I have to do it?
I'm sorry.
That's right... your handwriting is right on.
It's like Hawaii, isn't it?
Yeah, it's very Hawaiian.
I wonder if they sell it in Hawaii.
I think they do.
Oh, it's ready.
It's done.
Wow, it's done.
Thank you for waiting.
It's done.It's done.
Thank you very much.
Then, cover all the empty spaces on the glass that are now visible with curing tape.
If not, the outside of the glass will also be scraped off when the snack is put on, so we will cover it tightly so that there will be no gaps.
It's okay if we go a little overboard, right?
Yes.
When you come on a trip, you can do this kind of work, and it will become a memorable white.
You know, I just put it between my pinky finger and my toe,
I heard that there are paragliding and balloon rides here,
What?
I think this is something we have to do.
You've been saying that for a long time, haven't you?
Yes, I have. Seriously, since I was about 18, my dream has been to paraglide.
So it's to fly.
Yes, yes, yes.
It's not that easy, is it?
No, it's not. I heard that it's not available now because of the season, but..,
I see. It's just the season.
It's cold.
So, when they reopen, when they reopen in season, I would love to see them in the corps.
Well, I think it's a good memory.
I think it's a good memory. I'm going to call it "Hazuki Yuuna Finally Flying,
I really want to fly, so I'm going to do it.
Oh, please.
Oh, you can even experience something like that?
That's amazing. I can do anything.
I can stay here forever.
By the way, the experience here today is by reservation only,
Oh, I see.
You should come to Sendai when you come to Japan.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So it's inevitably the day after a concert or an event.
Maybe so.
But everyone comes to play.
People with weapons have cars, don't they?
That's for sure.
Tanabata Beach.
The ocean is beautiful.
People often ask me for recommendations.
Yes, they do.
So, if you come here, we can make you a wonderful gift, a one-of-a-kind cup.
That's right.
Then, no.
Ah.
Maybe fast-forward here.
Hey.
I'll do the "beeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeee!
It's done, right?
I'm sure it is. I'm sure it's done.
So, um, I'm sure it's cut,
I just finished putting the masking tape around this area.
I've finished putting it on the areas that won't get scratched.
It was quite detailed work.
From here, the final adjustments were made,
Then it's time to handglass?
Sanding.
Sandgrinding.
Sandgrinding is the process of sanding.
Wow.
So that's the next step?
Yes, that's right.
Then the next step is the real work.
Yes.
It's finally time, isn't it?
Yes. This was the preparation for tomorrow.
So, I would like to go to the show.
Go.
Now, this next process, please.
Please.
At this time, please show me the hand blast behind you.
Hand blasting, wow.
This is a sand-blasting machine, and you will be doing the actual sand-blasting engraving.
I see.
So you are going to spray sand on the place where we have removed the seal, right?
I see. I understand.
Then, go ahead.
OK.
I'm going.
Watch over everyone.
Okay. I'll let you out.
Please do.
Wow, wow, wow, wow!
Wow, it's like a sandstorm.
Inside.
That's so funny!
Are you getting this?
Ha-ha-ha-ha.
I can't see.
Wow, it's like construction.
Easy?
Easy! So easy!
Oh, this is so much fun.
It's exciting.
I'll be a glassblower in the future.
I'll be a glassblower and a farmer for the rest of my life.
It's kind of handmade, isn't it?
Yes, I think I'll probably be fine.
Wow.
I wonder if it's clean.
It's fine.
Thank goodness!
No!
Then I'll do the next one too.
Yeah!
Okay?
Okay, okay.
Here you go.
I'm going to move my right hand.
I'm gonna move my right hand.
Yes, that's it. You see?
It's changing color.
It's changing.
Yes, it's changing.
And now...
Yes, sir.
Is that okay?
Yes, I'm good.
Let's move on.
Hold on a second, sir.
Here you go.
Okay. Okay.
Here we go.
Okay, okay. Here you go.
Has this changed color yet? Name.
Name, yes, okay?
Are you sure?
Yes. And the last check.
Oh, last check.
Oh, I'm fine then.
Okay.
Oh, it's done!
Thanks to your finishing touches.
I'm so glad!
I knew it!
Hey, it looks good!
This is the final stage of removing the tape from the cup I damaged earlier.
I want to use hot water to peel it off.
I'll probably peel all of this off and then I can see what's going on.
I hope it's okay.
Is it still there?
I have no idea.
Oh, oh, it's attached, it's attached.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my gosh.
That's huge.
Here we go.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, it's so cute.
Oh, wow.
It's so beautiful!
I didn't know it was that easy.
Amazing! I'm impressed!Amazing! I'm impressed!
It's so good!
I want to drink this hot water!
I just worked so hard!
That's amazing! It's so cute!
It's done!
I know it's hard to see, but it looks so bright to our eyes!
Ta-da!
It's so cute!
Today, we had a hands-on experience at Kiko, a glass design studio here in Tanabata Beach.
We did it with a machine called sandblasting...
It looked like it was broadcasting more sparks than usual.
I thought it looked hot.
I had this image of it.
I thought it was going to be like this when I came here today.
It's not dangerous at all. It's safe, easy, and cute.
It's not dangerous at all, it's safe and easy, and it's cute.
There's a table for little kids.
Yes, it's fun for the whole family to come.
Anyone can do it.
You can make one in the world as a gift.
That would be nice.
It's a great location.
It's beautiful.
It makes you want to make other things, too.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I want to make a series of dinosaurs.
Dinosaur series.
That's good. That's good.
I'll make it.
I'll make more than just cups.
I mean, not just cups, but...
Bottles...
Or plates... You can do that, too, right?
Like tiny ones.
It's so cute!
They have mugs and stuff.
There are nine of us, so it's hard to tell who's who.
That's for sure.
Maybe we should put them in here.
So we made glass cups this time.
I would like to drink good water with it!
Thank you very much.
I hope you all will try making your own glass cups.
Come and visit us!
Cheers!